AARON CIAGHI

Researcher - Full stack developer

aaron.ciaghi@gmail.com

+39 333 4366364

via Marsilli 7, 38068 Rovereto, Italy

Github: aaronsama

LinkedIn: aaron.ciaghi

Twitter: a2ronsama

Skype: a2ron-sama

Technologies

Backend

Ruby, Ruby on Rails

Frontend

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, React/Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, MDL/MCW

Devops

Docker

Languages

Italian - native

English - fluent

Bio

I'm a resarcher in ICT and a full stack developer with 5+ years of experience in Agile software development in Ruby on Rails. My current focus is on the design and implementation of web/mobile applications that address social issues and for rural areas in the Global South.

Work experience

> Fondazione Bruno Kessler - ICT Research Centre

Researcher, 2014 - present

Managed and actively involved in software projects for social good. Coordinated the writing of grant proposals (including FP7 and H2020). Conducted research in ICT4D and Food Waste supply chain. Organized and conducted training in Mozambique and South Africa on Agile software development. Supervised students, junior developers, BS and MS computer science theses.

> Horecapp s.r.l.s.

Senior Developer, 2017

Developed a progressive web application for beverage wholesalers to receive orders directly from their clients. Responsibilities included leading the development process using Agile methods, supporting clients in the transition and business development.

Japanese - intermediate

Portuguese - basic

German - basic

Mandarin Chinese - basic

Volunteering

AFS Intercultural Programs (since 2002): currently founder and president of my area's chapter.

Yomoyamabanashi (since 2007): board member in 2010-2014

Fun fact

This resume was generated with my fork of <u>node-resume</u> and is also available in JSON format.

Belka s.r.l.

Consulting Developer, 2015

Bootstrapped the development of a mobile application for peer-topeer delivery using Ionic, Cordova and AngularJS. This included the introduction of coding standards and best practices.

Projects

BringTheFood Ristorazione

Web application for charities and canteens to track food waste and donate the daily surplus. Contributed to doubling the donations received from canteens by the local food bank.

https://ristorazione.bringfood.org

BringTheFood

Web application and API for charities and donors of food surplus. https://www.bringfood.org/

> Commonfare Story Builder

React component for the Commonfare platform to write articles in multiple languages.

https://www.commonfare.net

Sea for All

Boat sharing web application. (side project)

https://www.seaforall.com

SAMo - Social Accountability for Mozambique

Web application and API to help citizens support Governments in assessing the current status of facilities in Mozambique's rural areas.

http://ict4sa.org/samo

Education

> 2010 - 2014 University of Trento - PhD in Inform

University of Trento - PhD in Information and Communication Technologies

2007 - 2010

University of Trento and Georgia Institute of Technology - MS Degree in Computer Science

> 2004 - 2007 University of Trento - BS Degree in Computer Science